On April 8th, the World Bank told South Asia
to keep doing more industrial policy.
They forgot to ask one question.
Can the workers actually be there?
THE HEAT FLOOR
Every six months, the World Bank publishes
the South Asia Economic Update.
The April 2026 edition has a headline number —
growth slowing to 6.3 percent.
South Asia uses industrial policy at roughly
twice the rate of other emerging markets.
The sector that creates the most non-farm jobs
isn't manufacturing. It's services.
Here's what the report doesn't measure.
Between 2001 and 2020, India lost roughly
259 billion working hours per year to heat.
A 1°C rise in mean temperature
cut net earnings by 16 percent.
A 1°C rise in wet-bulb temperature
cut earnings by 19 percent.
Informal-sector workers were 17 times more likely
to lose earnings on heat-stressed days.
Now overlay this on the manufacturing map.
In 2021, four economists published a paper
in the Journal of Political Economy.
Hot days reduce within-shift productivity.
Hot days reduce attendance.
Adaptation is real.
Adaptation is incomplete.
What does industrial policy buy you
if labor is wet-bulb-bounded?
Three redesigns follow.
One. Cooling infrastructure
as industrial subsidy.
Two. Follow the jobs engine
into services.
Three. Parametric heat-day insurance
for informal workers.
Here's where you build it.
Try the ImpactMojo Policy Advocacy Lab.
Climate Action Game.
Real Middle India.
ImpactMojo. Free development education for South Asia.